Bull and Dodd family papers
Connecticut Historical Society
Bull and Dodd Family Papers
1682-1885
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Bull family
0.25 linear feet (1/2 box)
Biographical Sketch
Jonathan Bull (1649-1702) was born in Hartford, Connecticut shortly after that city’s settlement. He went by the title Captain and/or Major. He and his wife Sarah Whiting Bull had eight children. Their oldest son, Jonathan (1696-1765) trained and worked as a physician and married Hannah Beach, with whom he had two children, Jonathan and Hannah.
Jonathan Bull (1746-1825) was the fourth generation of his family to live in Hartford. He was a distinguished lawyer and judge, having graduated from Yale in 1765. In 1810 Thomas Jefferson appointed him Commissioner of Loans for Connecticut. He married Delia Seymour, the daughter of Jerred and Deliverance Skinner Seymour. Their surviving children included Delia, who married Thomas Tisdall as his second wife, Elizabeth who married James Dodd as his second wife in 1834, Charles, and Cornelia, who married James Dodd as his first wife in 1815.
Hartford Postmaster John Dodd (1745-1809) with his first wife had children John, Henry, and Sally. He married as his second wife Mary Steel, daughter of James and Mary Skinner Steel and they had one child, James (b. 1786) who married Cornelia Bull and then her sister, Elizabeth Bull. Son John died one day after his father in 1809.
Scope and Content
The collection primarily consists of deeds for land in Hartford, specifically South Meadow, to members of the Bull family. Some of these deeds represent the earliest Hartford deeds in the CHS collection. All three Jonathan Bull’s bought and sold property.
Of interest in the deeds of Jonathan Bull (1649-1702) is a deed signed by Thomas Hooker (not the founder of Hartford) and one signed by a woman, Sarah Wells. The papers of Jonathan Bull (1746-1825) include letters written to him as Commissioner of Loans from the Treasury of the United States. One of the signatories was Albert Gallatin. Jonathan’s appointments as Commissioner are signed by Thomas Jefferson, President, and Secretary of State James Madison. Other Bull family members, namely Jonathan (1746-1825), and his grandchildren Elizabeth, Hannah, Charles and Henry, are represented by estate inventories, deeds, correspondence, and memorial poems to Hannah, which were published in the newspaper at her death in 1809.
A separate file of Hartford Land Records was created (Folder 10) to hold documents with no obvious direct tie to the Bull family. These include deeds, and several hand drawn maps of Hartford, none of which are dated.
Significant among John Dodd’s papers are a multi-paged inventory of his estate taken at the time of his death in 1809. A letter to G. Granger notifies him of Dodd’s death and the need to appoint a new person to the post. John Dodd, his wife Mary and their son John all died within a week of each other from spotted fever. James Dodd is represented by deeds, financial records, and incoming correspondence.
Zebulon Seymour (1709-1765), the husband of Keziah Bull and a Hartford joiner, has papers included in this collection. They consist of orders for payment and other financial correspondence, 1765-1790, and a 1779 certificate giving Seymour permission to build a dam, gristmill, and saw mill on the Little River in Hartford. In other Seymour family papers is an account of ordnance tuned into store at Hartford January 1, 1777, for use of the State Guard under the command of Israel Seymour, signed by Oliver Ellsworth.
Also in this collection are several newspaper clippings and an 1819 letter written by artist Sarah Goodridge (1788-1853).
Among the unidentified items are what appear to be a series of letters from a person (E.W.?) on board a vessel traveling the Erie Canal from Rochester to Albany, NY. The genealogical notes are on the Bull, Stee(e), Dodd and Tisdale families.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Bull, Jonathan, 1649-1702.; Dodd, John.; Seymour, Zebulon, 1709-1765.
Family Names
Dodd family.
Subjects
Deeds -- Connecticut -- Hartford.
Contents:
- Papers
  - Jonathan Bull (1649-1702). Deeds, 1682-1717. (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Includes deeds to his widow Sarah.
  - Jonathan Bull (1696-1765). Deeds., 1721-1745 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Jonathan Bull (1696-1765). Estate inventory (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Jonathan Bull (1746-1825). Letters from the U.S. Treasury department, Includes signature of Albert Gallatin (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
  - Jonathan Bull (1746-1825). Deeds, 1787-1812 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Jonathan Bull (1746-1825). Legal documents, 1807-1810.; Includes appointment as Commissioner by Thomas Jefferson. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Jonathan Bull (1746-1825). Incoming correspondence, 1798, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hartford Land records. Deeds and maps, 1695-1800, undated. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Charles Bull. Deeds, 1832, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Charles A. Bull. Letter to Charles B. Dodd, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Elizabeth Bull. Incoming correspondence, 1808-1828 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hannah Bull. Memorial poems, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Henry Bull. Letters to Charles Bull, 1812-1814 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - John Dodd. Deeds, 1765-1797 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - John Dodd. Estate inventory, ca. 1775; bill, 1767 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - John Dodd. Financial memoranda and correspondence, 1767-1809 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - James Dodd. Deeds, 1811, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - James Dodd. Financial records, 1811-1828 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - James Dodd. Incoming correspondence, 1811-1848 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Assorted Bull family documents, 1803, 1871, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Assorted Dodd family documents, 1808, 1820, 1850, 1886, 1888.; Includes Charles B. Dodd’s undated collection of autographs and a lock of "Jimmy’s" hair. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Zebulon Seymour. Correspondence, certificate to build a mill, 1765-1790 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Assorted Seymour family documents, 1777, 1832, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Newspaper clippings about and an 1819 letter from Sarah Goodridge (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Unidentified items (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Genealogical notes (Box 1, Folder 28)